Feelin' alive!
- Agent Lisbon?
- Hey. Patrick Jane, consultant.
- Hello.
- Morning, sheriff.
Hi. Trey Hughes.
Thanks for coming. It's, uh...
- Tell us about the victim.
- Look, hawk.
Family of haw... oh, they're gone.
- Rick Loomis, been in town five months.
- Wow.
Dead in his truck by the creek.
Well, maybe he died of happiness.
Too much natural beauty,
It's the Stendhal Syndrome.
- No. He was shot in the head.
- No?
Oh, well. Never mind.
Beautiful!
Who found the body
all the way out here?
Another prospector saw
Loomis' body in the truck yesterday
thought he was sleeping.
Then she came back this morning
and saw him, and checked
and saw he was shot dead.
- A prospector, you say?
- Yeah, for gold.
A guy discovered trace gold
in these hills about a year ago
got on the TV news about it.
Folks haven't stopped comin'
ever since.
Like a gold rush.
Yeah. Well, gold's over 1,300 an ounce
and unemployment's at 12%.
Got a lotta hard-nosed,
well-motivated folks here.
I don't blame 'em.
Poor souls gonna be disappointed.
Poor souls? There's no gold?
Oh, yeah, there's still some
in the stream bed. Always has been.
But... it's enough to pay
for your lodging, food
if you work hard to get it
but there's no El Dorado here.
I tell 'em that, but they don't listen.
Murder weapon?
Nothin' yet.
Hey, fellas.
How about you look around for the gun?
- Jane!
- Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Sorry, sorry.
I didn't touch a thing.
Our victim liked smooth jazz
yet his radio station
was tuned to heavy metal
which suggests that the jazz-hating killer
popped out the CD and found
music more to his taste
while he drove the truck over here
probably with the victim
already dead in the back.
I'll have forensics dust for prints.
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Excuse me. Hi.
Hi, Melinda.
That's Melinda.
She's the one who found Loomis' body.
Hi. Melinda Drew. Hi.
Um, you guys aren't gonna
be much longer, are you?
I mean, no disrespect
to the dead fella
but we're losing daylight.
Yeah, we'll do the best we can.
Ma'am, just stay behind the tape.
Now when did you first see the truck?
Uh, truck was here when I started work
yesterday, around 6:00 A.M.
And did Mr. Loomis work
up here often?
Uh, no, I-I haven't seen him
around here in a while.
May we get back to work now, ma'am?
Please?
It'll be soon, I expect.
Just stay behind the yellow tape.
Gold!
Hey, that's my equipment.
- There's more!
- CBI!
- Oh, it's so cool!
- That's mine!
- Relax.
- That gold belongs to me!
Now, we're not gonna do anything...
- That's no fair! They're letting her in!
- No! No, they aren't!
This is a... Back up!
This is a crime scene!
Hey, hey!
Are you insane?
Ow... my ankle.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
- It's red. That's good.
- How can red be good?
Well, blue means torn ligaments
and red means it's a sprain.
Sprain can be as bad as a break.
It's not sprained. Let's focus here.
- Job, murder, talk to me.
- Rick Loomis, 43.
Moved to Hadley six months ago
with his son and girlfriend.
Lives in a trailer home
near the gold panning creek.
We got something on the kill shot.
Bullet was from a colt .45.
- A colt? How wild west-y.
- Yup.
Plus, the lack of blood in the truck bed
means Jane was right.
The victim was shot somewhere else
and driven to the creek.
- Any prints?
- Only the victim's.
He's been dead awhile, the coroner says
two days at least.
I'll head back to Hadley,
corral Jane
go and see the girlfriend and the son.
The guy's gone for two days,
and they don't report him missing?
Rigsby and I can go.
You should stay off that ankle.
I'm fine. I'll go.
Agent Hightower, hi.
Um, I heard you took a fall.
I'm fine.
Ow! I'm fine.
So I pull out the topo map
there's a creek running
right through the claim.
I found a nugget the first day.
Yeah. Once you get that first hit
it's like a drug.
I mean, you just can't stop.
Yeah, sounds exciting.
So can I just show up and start panning
or digging or what have you
or do I need a permit
or a license or something?
- Check.
- No. All you gotta do to stake a claim
is find open public land,
and then you gotta mark it
and register with the government
and stuff. Five.
I'll call that.
Wes Attwood will sell you one that's already
registered, too if you want.
It saves you time.
Raise you 10.
Okay, well, uh, I'm gonna see your 15
and I'm gonna raise you
the same.
Sheriff says there's nothing up there.
He says that you guys
are just kidding yourselves.
Yeah, he would say that.
- He would?
- All these townspeople
own claims up in these hills themselves
so...
Exactly, and they wanna
keep it all for themselves.
I'm gonna call you.
Stands to reason.
Oh... that's my ride.
Well, folks, uh...
- It's been fun, but...
- What?
I have to go.
Well, come on. You can't just leave.
We barely took any of your money.
Two pair, busted flush, pair of Jacks.
Don't let us keep you.
Hey, Lisbon.
But no. Hightower.
I didn't even know you had legs.
Let's go.
- What were you doing back there?
- Five card draw.
- For money?
- No. For gold.
Oh, gold. Gold.
That makes it all right, then.
And gossip.
Victim Rick Loomis was
a former software developer.
Came up here after he got laid off.
His girlfriend is Cheryl Meade.
They've been together since his divorce.
Rick enjoyed working on his truck
with his son Jeff
age 17 and smart, but a little hostile.
You seem a little keyed up, Madeleine.
Something wrong?
Something personal?
None of your business.
Okay.
We're sorry for your loss, miss Meade,
Jeff, but we need to know
why you didn't file
a missing person's report for Rick.
Well, Rick had been, uh,
mining off the grid recently
away from his regular
claim near the creek.
Sometimes my dad
would be gone for a few days
and he'd never call to let us know.
Good school.
How's it been going...
your dad's gold claim?
- Great at first...
- Then nothing but mud.
It would've come good eventually.
He would've hit pay dirt.
- Wes Attwood sell him that claim?
- Yeah. Mr. Attwood.
Did, um, Rick carry a gun
with him
when he would go off by himself?
No. Rick didn't believe in guns.
- He didn't think guns exist?
- No, he didn't like them.
Me neither. Terribly dangerous.
Have you seen the statistics
on police shootings?
One bullet out of every ten
hits a bad guy.
And that's the trained people.
No offense.
This is not useful. Can I go now?
Yeah, sure.
It was Rick's idea
to come out here, wasn't it?
To follow the gold dream.
When Rick had a passion,
there was no stopping him.
I loved that about him.
But you had to give up
a successful career of your own.
High-end sales type of business.
Following someone else's dream
must be, uh...
At times, a little frustrating.
We all made sacrifices.
Jeff put off going to college.
Oh. Rick raided the college fund, did he?
Yeah. We're broke.
Okay, we're flat broke. But...
We had each other.
Cheryl, look at me.
There's no need to pretend
and I mean that in the nicest possible way
but there's a whole lot of guilt
in there with that grief
and just a smidgen,
just a smidgen, of relief.
Right? Were you cheating on Loomis?
- No!
- Patrick!
- Okay, just a thought.
You're guilty about something.
Where were you on Monday night
when he was murdered?
I, I was at the diner, waitressing.
I can't believe that you think
that I would hurt him.
All right. Okay.
I'll be leaving right now.
Sorry.
There was no reason
to treat her disrespectfully.
I was probing her.
A certain amount of disrespect
is necessary. It's, uh...
It's like getting frisked at the airport.
Probing. All right.
Okay. Well, she did seem like
she was hiding something.
I'll get the team
to look into her financials
while we talk to sheriff Hughes.
Well, that sounds fun.
I bet there's a good diner in town
where you can drop me off.
I bet there is. Why don't I do that?
Tell a lot about a place
by the quality of the eggs.
Checked into the bank records.
Victim had an account with his girlfriend,
all of 88 dollars and 32 cents.
But here's the thing. Cheryl Meade,
she had a separate account
her name only, over 5 grand.
The girlfriend? She told Hightower
she was flat broke.
She lied.
Cheryl Meade also bought
a one-way ticket
to San Francisco a week ago.
Well, maybe she wanted to put
some distance
between herself and a dead boyfriend.
Rick Loomis recently bought a gun.
Colt .45, same make
as the murder weapon.
The girlfriend told Hightower
Loomis didn't own one.
- So either she knew about it or...
- Or she's lying about that, too.
- Well, let's bring her in here.
- Don't worry, boss.
We already got it covered.
Okay. I'll just stay here and, um...
Not do anything.
"Hello?"
Mr. Attwood? Anyone home?
I'm Wes Attwood. How you doing?
- You're the police, right?
- Well, more of a hobbyist.
Patrick Jane. Your assistant told me
where to find you.
Hey, I'm Dean Puttock.
Nice to meet you.
After I sell you a claim
Dean will sell you anything
you need to find gold.
Sluices, high-bankers, pans...
he's the go-to guy.
That's right. We got a 10% off sale
on pumps all week long, so...
- Good to know.
- Yeah.
I gotta get back to the shop. You guys
need anything, let me know.
- Okay.
- Good seeing you. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too, Dean.
Hey, you folks mind if I join you?
Just to get a feel for the place?
Uh... I don't know.
Wes, we're the customers, right?
Sure thing, Sonya, but...
the more, the merrier, Mr. Jane.
Just showing Jack and Sonya here
a claim I have for sale.
- Watch and learn.
- All right.
All right.
You knew Rick Loomis, didn't you?
The, uh, miner that died in the park?
Yeah. Yeah, I sold Loomis a claim
when he first got to Hadley.
- Real tragedy. Nice guy.
- Ah.
So, it's the bends in the river
where you're gonna find the gold, you see?
- Uh-huh.
- Okay.
It's heavier, so it falls into the silt.
You just gotta wash the silt away...
What do you see there?
Oh, my God. Jack, gold.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my...
I wonder what it's worth.
Did you know only 10% of the gold
in the Sierra Nevadas
was found during the original gold rush?
Billions of dollars are out there...
Just waiting to be discovered.
Can I see?
Um... yeah.
Wow.
- Yeah.
- It's cool.
Yeah. Hey, Wes...
Wanna try just here?
How about we let the new owners
pan over there?
Well, I'll take it.
- Hey, hey. We... We get first dibs.
- Hang on, pal.
Dibs? What are we? Children?
I'm just kidding. It's all yours.
Do you have another claim
you can sell me?
- Yeah, I-I do have other claims.
- Yeah?
Great spots, but, uh...
- Aren't you here on police business?
- Yeah. So?
It doesn't mean I can't mine for gold.
- Do whatever I want.
- Okay. Sure thing.
Cool.
I got another super-hot site.
Black sand and quartz all up
and down the bed stream.
Black sand and quartz...
that's the good stuff, isn't it?
- Yup. This is the site for you.
- Oh, yeah.
It's up the creek there
about half a mile.
- And where are we here?
- About here.
Okay. So can we go
take a look at it now?
You know, I'm, I'm kinda jammed
today, but, uh...
What do you say
I meet you in the parking lot
bright and early tomorrow morning?
Say, 8:00 A.M.?
Tomorrow at 8:00 A.M.
in the parking lot.
- Look forward to it.
- Good.
Yeah, well, good luck to you.
Oh, I won't need luck.
I'm feeling the gold.
I feel rich already.
- You take it easy.
- Yeah.
- That's the spirit. Good.
- I'll see you later. 8:00 A.M.
All right.
Rick owns a colt .45.
Where is it?
A gun?
Rick?
What would Rick need a gun for?
You also told us you were broke,
but you have $5,000.
That's not broke.
That's my money, and you can't
touch it.
We don't plan on touching it.
Where'd you get it?
Waitressing.
$5,000 tucked away.
And you booked a seat on flight 465
to San Fran for this morning.
No. I mean...
I mean, ye...
I booked that a week ago.
- Before he died.
- Exactly. It looks like a plan.
- Some plan. I didn't go, did I?
- Why not?
Because I knew it would look bad.
Why were you planning on going?
'Cause I was... leaving Rick.
I couldn't take it here anymore.
- Did Rick know that?
- No.
Rick was blind to everything
but the gold.
He's been like that
ever since we got here.
He, he would find a little nugget
and he would get all excited
and come running in
saying,
"We're rich. I hit the mother lode."
The first three times, I believed him
and then after the 20th time,
I couldn't take it anymore.
Look, I loved him. I did.
But I fell in love
with a regular guy
with an apartment
and a job and clean clothes
not some obsessive
scratching in the dirt.
But I need you to know, I'm...
I'm not a bad person.
I don't make that kind of evaluation.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Do you know which store
is Wes Attwood's?
Yep.
You wanna tell me?
Right there.
Thank you.
'Course, it's not open right now.
Of course.
- Do you know how I can contact him?
- Yep.
Uh, you don't wanna get her mad.
She's, uh, stressed enough already.
- Where have you been?
- In the diner.
Not when I went by there
several hours ago.
Good eggs.
Two loosely scrambled on toast
is the test
and these were just so.
Then I took a nice walk
in the countryside.
You know, there's no cell phone range
in these hills
which I find very refreshing.
I am going to go see Wes Attwood.
Perhaps you'll join me?
You're really committed to keeping
your temper contained, huh?
What's up with that?
You're really committed
to testing my temper, huh?
- What's up with that?
- Idle curiosity.
- What, what are you doing?
- I'm hiding from Wes Attwood.
- Why?
- Because we're gonna follow him.
- Okay.
- What's he doing?
- He's trying to defraud me.
His shotgun is filled with gold flakes.
He's salting the claims he sells
to make 'em appear richer.
Hey, Wes!
Looks like we're both a little early.
Whoa, whoa... easy.
- Put the gun down!
- Okay, okay.
- Put the shotgun down!
- Chill. Don't, don't shoot.
- I'm not resisting.
- Turn around.
- I'm not resisting...
Okay, okay.
Look, this is a misunderst...
You... you can't cuff me.
I haven't committed a crime.
Try pointing a gun at a police officer,
for starters. Move.
- This is outrageous.
- That's the spirit.
Gold in a shotgun cartridge.
Clever.
Mr. Attwood, let me lay it out for you.
Looks to us like Rick Loomis
caught you salting the gold claims.
"He would've been plenty mad."
"You would've had
to kill him to keep him quiet."
"Hey, now, I didn't kill anybody."
I mean, I'm a killer salesman, but...
You know, I'm not a killer.
Ask yourself whether this is the right
moment for humor, Mr. Attwood.
I am a seller of hope.
I was simply helping folks
visualize the future.
"Great marketing is not a crime."
"And I wouldn't murder anyone
to cover it up."
We'll see. We can hold you
on the fraud charges
and see about the murder as we go.
Oh, come on.
I can have a lawyer here in half an hour.
Be reasonable.
There's plenty of people
that could've killed that guy.
Fraud alone can get you ten years,
depending on the judge.
Have you even checked into the
sneak thief that's been targeting miners?
"Stealing their equipment?"
Loomis got hit ten days ago.
Bastard cleaned him out.
That's who killed him, I promise you.
If that's true, I wonder why
Sheriff Hughes didn't tell us about it.
That's why I hate
these small town investigations.
You never know if the guys
have done the math.
I'm gonna follow up with Hughes.
Ow.
- You good?
- Screw it. You go.
Yeah.
Why rob Loomis and
then kill him ten days later?
Maybe Loomis found out
who it was that stole from him
and confronted him.
Yeah. That must be what happened.
Something you care to share?
No. Sorry, just a funny thought, is all.
Can I go now,
or are you gonna charge me?
I'll let you know.
All right. That's odd.
Okay. Well, charge Wes Attwood
with fraud
if he can post bail, let him go
and put a name to this local thief.
All right.
Okay, so sheriff Hughes confirms
that there has been
a string of equipment thefts.
But he says that Rick Loomis
never filed a police report.
Hmm. Why not, we wonder?
Let's go talk sluice pumps.
- So you play bad cop.
- I'll be me, thank you.
- Right. Exactly what I said.
- Funny.
So funny.
I hit a big one.
Wow. They're huge.
- You cashing in?
- Hell, no!
Just when I hit good dirt? Nah.
I'm buying a better pump
and foot valves.
Hey, Mr. Jane. How ya doin'?
- Good. How are you?
- Good.
Oh, this is, uh, Special Agent Hightower.
We believe Rick Loomis bought some,
uh, new mining equipment from you
after his old equipment
had been stolen.
Yes, he did. He was in here,
I'd say, about nine days ago.
What did he buy?
Whole bunch of stuff.
He spent over 10 grand.
Maybe we could see an invoice?
Yeah. Give me a second.
I'll pull it up.
Um, would you mind terribly
if, if I held one of your, uh...
your nuggets in my hand?
- Mm... sure, I guess.
- Well...
Thank you.
Thanks.
A g-force rock crusher.
And a series 54 Pulverizer?
Man. I wish I had one of those.
That's the, that's the best
for hard rock mining.
Yep. That's some good gear
for sure.
Hard rock mining, is that in the creek?
No, no. Creek panning's
a whole other thing.
Hard rock, it's like it sounds.
Uh, dry mining up in the hills.
Did he mention to you that his mining
equipment had been stolen?
He didn't. He said that he got
sick and tired of panning.
Wanted to try something new.
Seemed a little bit like a hail Mary
desperation kinda play to me.
But hey, chasing his dream, you know?
He never did have any patience.
You know, God rest his soul.
Right. Thank you.
Hey!
You got me. Worth a try.
Sorry, ma'am.
- Hello?
- Ma'am? Rigsby.
So, we may have found our thief.
Scott Munroe.
He's a townie with a long rap sheet.
Assault with a deadly weapon,
B&E, and, wait for it...
stealing mining equipment.
"Got outta prison six months ago."
Good work. Scott Munroe.
You got an address?
Yeah, I'm gonna send it to you...
"Rigsby? An address?"
Uh, y-yes, ma'am.
Your kids are here?
What?
Ma'am? Your, uh, husband
had to go somewhere, I guess.
He left Mimi and Will
with Jean at the front desk.
Damn. Damn. Damn.
Lisbon here.
Listen, don't worry.
We can look after them until you get back.
Lisbon, thank you.
I appreciate it, truly.
I, um...
Thank you.
May I have a word with Mimi, please?
All right. It's your mom.
Hi, mommy.
- Hi, baby. You okay?
- "Uh-huh."
Look, I'm gonna be back
in a few hours
but I want you to, uh, be a good girl
and I want you to listen
to what Ms. Lisbon says
and I want you to look after
your brother, okay?
- Okay.
- Mimi, I love you.
- Bye.
So, uh...
Who's Scott Munroe?
Local mining equipment thief.
Excellent.
Let's go talk to him, shall we?
Thanks for not asking questions.
Oh, no need to ask questions
when you know all the answers.
So...
- Cookies?
- Okay.
- Are you disabled?
- No. No, I'm injured.
Not that disabled is bad, but I'm not.
I'm injured.
You walk like disabled.
So, no questions, but, uh...
we can talk if you want.
Talk about what?
- I'll take that as a no.
- Yes. No.
Scott?
Scott Munroe?
CBI.
Oh, hell...
Is it Scott Munroe?
No. Wes Attwood.
Gold claims dealer.
That's odd.
- Odd?
- It's sad, too, but I'm...
I'm just saying it's odd...
that it's not Scott Munroe.
- Where's Mimi and will?
- Tearing up paper in my office.
- What's going on with Munroe?
- Well, we've got a BOLO out
and Sheriff Hughes
is putting up roadblocks.
Hadley's pretty much on lockdown.
Why would Munroe kill Attwood?
Well, maybe he was conducting
an investigation of his own.
You know, trying to figure out
if Munroe killed Loomis.
Found out the hard way.
Rigsby.
No, don't move in. You'll scare him off.
We're leaving now.
Munroe's been spotted in a local bar
that his cousin works at.
Go. Both of you.
Hey, boss.
No, they're fine.
Y-yeah. Uh-huh.
Uh-huh.
All right.
All right. Hold on a second.
Whoa! Look at this!
Excellent work, guys.
Now, we are gonna take this paper
and put it in these bags.
But first, say hi to mommy.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hey, mommy, guess what?
- We're tearing up paper.
Tearing up paper?
Okay.
All right.
Well, Mimi, eat all your snack, okay?
All right. I love you.
Give the phone back to,
um, Agent Lisbon for me.
Okay.
Hey. You're sending Rigsby
and Van Pelt?
Okay, great.
Keep me apprised on Monroe.
All right. Thanks. Bye.
Chamomile tea...
excellent for repressed anger.
- I'm not angry.
- Sure, you are.
Letting it out would be helpful,
I guarantee it.
Shout. Scream.
Hit something, preferably not me.
It'll do you wonders.
You only think you know
all the answers, Patrick.
You don't.
You're getting a divorce.
And now your husband is acting out.
He just showed up
and left the kids with you.
How'd you know
I was getting a divorce?
Your posture.
The look in your eyes.
Your wedding ring, it's gone.
You've been having trouble
for years.
Trying to make it work for the kids.
Plus, uh, everyone in the office knows.
Water cooler talk.
Depends on who you're speaking with
you cheated on him or he cheated on you
- and you've just had enough, so...
- Okay.
Okay.
Let's keep the focus
on the business at hand, okay?
Why would Munroe first kill Loomis,
and then Attwood?
What's, what's the connection?
Mm. My question is this...
why did the killer shoot Loomis
and then drive the body
all the way to the creek?
Well, not to hide the body.
He left it in plain sight, so...
He didn't want the body found
at the kill site.
Exactly. Why not?
Van Pelt and Rigsby
are gonna pick up Scott Munroe.
We'll ask him.
Club soda, please.
How about something
a little stronger?
I'm buying.
Oh, hey. Scott, right?
Scott Munroe?
Yeah.
That's funny, 'cause
I've been looking for you.
Later, bitch.
- What the hell?
- What? She's a cop.
Yeah. Me, too.
Up against the wall.
Put your hands
behind your back.
- Theresa?
- Yes, Mimi?
- I'm done with my math homework.
- Good work.
- Did you check it?
- No.
- Check it, please.
- Okay.
- After homework, can we watch TV?
- Nope.
Hi. We got Monroe.
You two stay here.
After you finish your homework
you can have another snack,
they're on my desk.
Need some help?
And then TV?
And then Agent Rigsby
will tell you a story.
Mr. Munroe, tell us what happened
with Loomis and Attwood.
I have no idea, except they're dead.
Yeah, Attwood was dead
on the floor of your trailer.
Man, this is a frame-up.
Maybe I should be talking to my lawyer.
That's your right, of course.
But this doesn't need to be adversarial.
- Just clear a few things up for us.
- What do you wanna know?
We're told you're the top thief
in Hadley.
You specialize
in gold mining equipment.
We hear you're the best at it.
It's good to be the best
at something, right, Scott?
That stuff holds up
its resale value real well.
And you killed Attwood because
he found out you killed Loomis.
You killed Loomis because he found out
you stole his equipment.
Hey, you know
who stole Loomis' equipment?
His own kid, Jeff.
Yeah. I'm blowing your mind, right?
The kid came to me last week
to unload the stuff.
I bought the whole lot
for a hundred bucks.
Cold little bastard.
Call Hightower.
Your father's mining equipment
was recently stolen.
- Do you know anything about that?
- No.
So it wasn't you who stole
your father's equipment?
- No. It's not true.
- Oh, come on, Jeff.
You were mad at him.
We get it.
I wasn't mad at him.
He cleaned out your college fund
and you weren't mad at him?
That's a... little odd, Jeff.
Talk to us, Jeff.
Help us make this right.
My grandparents gave me
that money.
If he had just asked me,
I would've said sure
but he tried to hide it from me.
So you got even by stealing
his panning equipment?
- Did your father find out?
- Oh, he knew it was Jeff all along.
That's why he didn't call
the police.
Did you two get into a fight?
Jeff, what happened?
What happened?
He wasn't even mad.
He said he was sorry...
about the college money,
about everything.
He promised to make it up to me.
I didn't wanna listen to him,
so I walked out.
And that was the last time
we ever spoke.
Well, that's too bad.
But I imagine owning
a gold mine will ease the guilt.
Do you have a map of the area?
- Huh?
- A map.
I think the "Huh?"
was for the gold mine part.
Ah. Yes.
Uh, Jeff, what did your dad
stop doing recently?
Washing himself?
No. Something else.
Uh...
What did your dad stop
saying recently?
He stopped saying...
that he found a gold mine.
Yes. Which could only mean
- Really?
- Really.
And Jeff is gonna tell us where it is.
I am? How?
Hey, guys. Can I help ya?
Yes. Uh, we need to look at a large-scale
map of the hill country.
- Got one right there on the table.
- Okay. Thank you.
Your father found gold, Jeff.
He knew you and Cheryl
wouldn't believe him.
He'd disappointed you
so many times before
so he wouldn't tell anyone, not a soul.
Not until he had that real gold
to put in your hand.
He told you nothing. He wanted to.
Badly. And subconsciously, he did.
Subconsciously, he told you
exactly where that gold is.
- So where is it?
- Yeah, where is it?
Honestly, I don't have any idea.
You and your father
were close, weren't you?
You loved one another?
- Yes.
You had a connection.
You know a lot more
than you think you know.
Let's take a look, shall we?
Give me your hand.
This is for your father. Trust me.
I need a physical connection to get
a good reading, please.
- All right.
- Thank you.
Now we're working together.
That's nice.
Now, just relax.
- Relax.
- All right.
What I'm doing is scanning
his unconscious
measuring his affinity.
Narrow it down...
You narrow it down...
To a more specific area.
Uh-huh.
Interesting.
- What is?
- Jane?
Yes.
Nope.
Never mind. Didn't work.
You said, "Uh-huh. Interesting."
Yes, I did. Uh, I thought
I was getting a location, but, uh...
I was wrong.
It's not an exact science, what I do.
No kidding.
Well, uh... I need
to go and get me some eggs.
- But what about the gold mine?
- Disappointing, I know
but, uh, you seem
like a smart young man.
I-I think you'll do fine.
Jane!
Hey!
Jane! Jane!
Hi, Dean.
Mr. Jane. I'm impressed.
You found it.
You really did scan
that kid's unconscious, or whatever.
No, that'd be magic.
So, then, how?
Well, I watched you watch
the boy's hand on the map
and got a general direction
then I waited for your truck
to go by and I followed you here.
It was you that led me to the gold.
Don't feel bad.
I assure you, better men
than you have been taken.
How'd you know it was me?
Rick Loomis preferred smooth jazz.
- You like the heavy metal.
- So?
So your disdain for mellow saxophone
solos has cost you dearly.
Did Rick Loomis tell you
he'd found a seam
or did you just follow him
on the off chance?
Look, Mr. Jane, with all due respect
my family has been up here
in Hadley mining
since the first gold rush.
"That gold belongs to me
to my family."
"Not to some newbie like Loomis."
Poor Wes Attwood. He figured out
the killer was you, didn't he?
Tried to blackmail you,
get a cut of that gold.
Hey, you believe the nerve
of that guy?
Greedy bastard.
You do hear the irony there, right?
Yeah, when I heard you cops
were lookin' for Scott Munroe
that made it easy.
I make it look like Munroe killed Attwood
and I'm off the hook for all of it.
Splendid plan.
The only thing standing between me
and my gold now, Mr. Jane...
- is you.
- Any time, Madeleine.
Drop it, Puttock!
No, screw that! You drop yours.
Drop it!
Son of a bitch.
Seriously?
Is he dead?
Yeah.
You know, I should applaud
your bravery
but I gotta say, practically speaking
I-I-I...
What were you thinking?
You coulda killed me!
I'm sorry.
I got mad.
I didn't know what I was thinking.
That was some good shooting, though.
That...
Leg shot that took him down
was v-very precise.
I was aiming for his head.
Oh, fantastic.
- Hey. Hey, Jeff.
- Hey.
I hear your mom's flying in.
Yeah, from Fresno.
I'm picking her up in the morning.
Kinda nervous about it.
It's been a while.
Buy her some flowers.
Moms like flowers.
And you can afford a good bunch.
We had that sent over from
the Bureau of Land Management.
You father was in the process
of filing a mineral rights claim
to the area where he struck gold.
He named you and Cheryl
as co-owners.
You own half a gold mine.
Wow, I...
You father came through in the end.
- Thanks for, uh... you know.
- You're welcome.
Hey, uh, will you, um...
thank Mr. Jane for me?
Will do. Will do.
Good luck to you, Jeff.
Thanks.
I hope they weren't too much trouble.
Not at all.
I had three nearly feral brothers.
Your kids are sweethearts.
Thank you.
Hey...
Not a problem.
Let me get 'em outta your hair.
Hello. Hello.
Get up! Get up!
Come on.
Give me some sugar.
Hey.
It was okay, then?
Case closed.
What was it like?
"It"?
You know...
Oh.
You mean going out
with another woman?
Yeah. No.
Uh, come on.
You know what I mean.
It was great.
It's fun, intense, um, challenging.
She's super dynamic.
Yeah. I think we had
a great connection.
That's great.
What, you a little jealous?